

LE ROUX VERMEULEN

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER • JOHANNESBURG, 1448, SOUTH AFRICA • +27 66 290 0869

• DETAILS •

27 Bamboes Street
Johannesburg, 1448
South Africa
+27 66 290 0869
lerouxvermeulen@gmail.com

• LINKS •

Github

Personal portfolio

Linkedin

SKILLS

JavaScript

CSS3

Vue

Flutter

Angular

TypeScript

Node.js

Android Development

React

Java

HOBBIES

Hiking
Camping
Playing instruments
Gaming
Simulation Racing
Mountain biking

LANGUAGES

Afrikaans

English

PROFILE

I am a dedicated self-taught web and software developer. After high school, I studied and graduated with a psychology degree, but I knew it was not what I wanted to do with my life. Technology has always interested me so I started to learn a bit of programming, and was hooked ever since. I have been doing web and software development since 2019. I think what gives me an edge is that I am passionate about this field and always want to learn more to further improve my skills. I didn't just go through a computer science degree because I had to, I learnt this because I wanted to, and had the drive to continue learning.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Front End Developer at Raging River Trading, Pretoria

November 2021 — Present

My main role at Raging River is to assist with the front-end development of the new Betway web app. Among the tech we use for the project are the front-end framework, Vue, the UI library Vuetify and the Vue framework Nuxt.

Some of my main responsibilities include implementing new features, fixing bugs and writing clean and maintainable code. I also have to ensure that the code I write is performant and tested well. I also have to communicate and coordinate with the back-end team from time to time to request new endpoints to be developed, or new data to be included in existing endpoints. I also have to communicate with the people on the business side of the project to ensure that requirements are met.

Junior Software Developer at Thinwood.co, Pretoria

 $July\,2021-November\,2021$

This was a fast paced startup environment where I had to constantly learn new technologies. We worked with the AGILE principles, using Jira and Bitbucket. I learned Angular with TypeScript and Android with Java for this job specifically and built angular and android apps respectively. My responsibilities also included designing and wire-framing app mockups with Miro.

Freelancer

June 2020 — June 2021

I have been casually freelancing on and off since I felt confident enough to do so. I have completed 3 official freelancing projects since mid 2020 together with a couple of my own personal apps (see portfolio and GitHub)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of arts, University of Pretoria, Pretoria

January 2015 — December 2017

I graduated with a Psychology and Sports Psychology Bachelor degree.

COURSES

The Web Developer Bootcamp, Udemy

CSS - The Complete Guide 2020 (incl. Flexbox, Grid & Sass) Certificate, Udemy

The Modern JavaScript Bootcamp Course Certificate, Udemy

Dart & Flutter - The Complete Guide, Udemy

MongoDB - The Complete Developers Guide, Udemy

Design Rules: Principles and Practices for Great Design, Udemy

Interactive Web Animation 2021 [JavaScript, SVG, CSS, HTML], Udemy

Complete Vue Mastery 2022 (w/ Vuex, Composition API, Router), Udemy

Angular - The Complete Guide (2022 Edition), Udemy

REFERENCES

Henrick Tissink from Raging River Trading
079 873 9233

Herco Bezuidenhout from Thinwood.co
064 652 3881

Mike Murray from Raging River Trading
083 678 7049

Jurie Vermeulen from Feba Radio

072 316 9562

Mario E Moural Garcez Palha from Manfex +27 82 950 7988